Think you're quick enough?
The Quick and the Dead is a western, action, drama film directed by Sam Raimi.
A mysterious woman comes to compete in a quick-draw elimination
tournament, in a town taken over by a notorious gunman.
Ellen, played by Sharon Stone.
John Herod, played by Gene Hackman.
Cort, played by Russell Crowe.
Kid, played by Leonardo DiCaprio.
Dog Kelly, played by Tobin Bell.
Doc Wallace, played by Roberts Blossom.
The Quick and the Dead is a 1995 American revisionist
Western film directed by Sam Raimi.
The film stars Sharon Stone, Gene Hackman, Russell Crowe, and Leonardo DiCaprio.
The screenplay was written by Simon Moore, but
includes contributions from Joss Whedon.
The story focuses on "The Lady" (Stone), a gunfighter who rides into the
frontier town of Redemption, controlled by John Herod (Hackman).
The Lady joins a deadly dueling competition in an attempt
to exact revenge for her father's death.
Simon Moore's script was purchased by Sony Pictures Entertainment in May 1993,
and actress Sharon Stone signed on as both star and co-producer.
Development was fast tracked after director Sam Raimi's hiring, and principal
photography began in Old Tucson Studios in Arizona on November 21, 1993.
The film was distributed by TriStar Pictures and was released in the United States on February 10,
1995, to a dismal box-office performance, receiving mixed reviews from critics.
In later years, however, the film has earned critical praise, especially for the performances, direction,
cinematography, and musical score, with some critics noting it as underrated in Raimi's catalog.
The film explores themes of gunslinger, revenge, prairie, shootout, awestruck.
The tone is emotional and intense.